Jerome-Alexis Chevalier

17. rue de Gassendi, 75017 Paris

□ +33 (0)6 65 64 02 78 | **□** jerome-alexis.chevalier@inria.fr | **□** ja-che

Summary.

PhD student in machine learning working on the statistical control of sparse models in high dimension with application in neuro-imaging. Passionate by probability, statistics and coding, started by working in finance for more than two years before changing of career for machine learning. Decided to do a PhD after a year of master in data science in order to gain serious theoretical knowledge and learn coding best practices.

Education

Telecom ParisTech and Inria Paris-Saclay

Paris

PHD CANDIDATE: STATISTICAL CONTROL OF SPARSE MODELS IN HIGH DIMENSION

2017 - 2020

- Worked on several models for high dimensional inference (Desparsified Lasso, Multi-Split, Corrected Ridge, Residual Bootstrap, ...)
- · Worked on clustering and ensembling techniques suited for statistical inference
- Developed an algorithm (Ensemble of Clustered Desparsified Lasso) adapted for the statistical inference on neuro-imaging problems
- Compared algorithms using several neuro-imaging datasets (HCP, IBC, Haxby, Oasis, ...)
- · Wrote research articles in English for machine learning conferences and journals
- Followed several machine learning courses (optimization, statistics in high dimension, kernel methods)

Universite Paris Diderot, Paris 7

Paris

MASTER OF SCIENCE: STATISTICS, PROBABILITY AND DATA SCIENCE (M2MO, EX-DEA LAURE ELIE)

2016 - 2017

· Machine Learning, Datamining, Probability, Statistics, Stochastic Calculus, Python, C++

Essec Busisness School

Paris 2013 - 2014

ADVANCED MASTER: FINANCIAL TECHNIQUES

Bordeaux

MASTER OF ENGINEERING: MATHEMATICAL MODELING AND MECHANICS

2010 - 2013

Bordeaux

PREPARATORY CLASS: MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

2008 - 2010

Publications

ENSEIRB-MATMECA

Lycee Michel Montaigne

MICCAI 2018 (Springer): Chevalier, J.A., Salmon, J., Thirion, B.: Statistical inference with ensemble of clustered desparsified lasso Under review: Chevalier, J.A., Nguyen, B., Thirion, B.: Ensemble of clustered knockoffs for robust multivariate inference on fMRI data

Experience

Telecom ParisTech and Inria Paris-Saclay

Paris

PHD CANDIDATE: STATISTICAL CONTROL OF SPARSE MODELS IN HIGH DIMENSION

Sen 2018 - Sen 2019

· Coding mission: contributed to Nilearn and Nistats machine learning libraries for neuro-imaging in Python

Amundi Alternative Investments

London

QUANTITATIVE ANALYST IN ALTERNATIVE INVESTMENTS

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Developed and maintained quantitative tools to optimize the fund selection
- Built and backtested an automatized activist investment strategy
- Contributed to the monthly allocation strategy outlooks working closely with three teams (Equity, FI, Macro)

BNP Paribas Investments Partners - THEAM

Paris

Nov. 2014 - Jun. 2015

- Managed a range of CPPI lifecycle funds (AuM Eur 1 billion)
- · Implemented the investment process including the risky asset allocation and the interest rate hedging
- · Developed investment tools to price OTC instruments, watch fund parameters and performance attribution

Oddo & Cie - Oddo Asset Management

QUANTITATIVE INVESTMENT ANALYST

Apr. 2014 - Oct. 2014

· Built style indexes (Value, Growth, Quality, ...) and smart beta strategies to monitor market trends and develop new funds

Skills.

FUND MANAGER

Languages: French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate)

Programming languages and Softwares: Python (Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib), R, C++, Latex, Git, Atom